<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<spells>
	<spell name="ANNIHLATION" cost="4" rng="10" aoe="3" pow="10" up="NO" off="YES"> Models hit suffer a POW 10 damage roll. Models boxed by Annihlation are removed from play. This model gains a soul token for each living non-soulless enemy model removed from play this way.</spell>
	<spell name="ASHEN VEIL" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model / unit gains concealment. Living enemy models suffer -2 to attack rolls while within 2" of an affected model.</spell>
	<spell name="BLAZING EFFIGY" cost="4" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="14" up="NO" off="NO">Enemy models within 2" of target friendly Faction warjack suffer a POW l4 fire damage roll.</spell>
	<spell name="BLEED" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="10" up="NO" off="YES">When Bleed destroys a living enemy model, this model heals d3 damage points. </spell>
	<spell name="BONE SHAKER" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">When this spell boxes a living or undead non-warcaster non-warlock enemy warrior model, you can immediately make a full advance with the enemy model followed by a normal melee attack, then the boxed model is removed from play. The boxed model cannot be targeted by free strikes during this movement.</spell>
	<spell name="BREATH OF CORRUPTION" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="3" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">Models hit suffer a POW l2 corrosion damage roll. The AOE is a cloud effect that remains in play for one round. Models entering or ending their activation in the AOE suffer 1 point of corrosion damage</spell>
	<spell name="CARNAGE" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Friendly Faction models gain +2 to melee attack rolls against enemy models in this model's control area. Carnage lasts for one turn.</spell>
	<spell name="CAUSTIC MIST" cost="2" rng="CTRL" aoe="3" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Place a 3" AOE cloud effect completely within this model’s control area. A model entering or ending its activation in the AOE suffers 1 point of corrosion damage   Caustic Mist lasts for one round.</spell>
	<spell name="CLEANSING FIRE" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="3" pow="14" up="NO" off="YES">Cleansing Fire causes fire damage. On a critical hit, models hit suffer the Fire continuous effect.</spell>
	<spell name="CONVECTION" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">When Convection destroys a living enemy model, allocate l focus point to a warjack in this model’s battlegroup that is in its control area.</spell>
	<spell name="CRIPPLING GRASP" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">Target model/unit suffers -2 SPD, STR, DEF, and ARM and cannot run or make special attacks.</spell>
	<spell name="CURSE OF SHADOWS" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">Target model/unit suffers -2 ARM and cannot make free strikes. A model can advance through an affected model if it has enough movement to move completely past its base.</spell>
	<spell name="DEATH KNELL" cost="4" rng="8" aoe="4" pow="10" up="NO" off="YES">Before dealing damage, count the number of models in the AOE. Add the result to each Death Knell damage roll.</spell>
	<spell name="DEFENDER’S WARD" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly Faction model/unit gains +2DEF and ARM.</spell>
	<spell name="ENGINE OF DESTRUCTION" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model gains +2 SPD, +4 STR, and +4 MAT for one round</spell>
	<spell name="ESCORT" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Warjacks in this model’s battlegroup beginning their activations in its control area gain +2" movement. This model gains +2 ARM while one or more warjacks in its battlegroup are within 3" of it.</spell>
	<spell name="EXCARNATE" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">When a living enemy warrior model is boxed by Excarnate, remove it from play. You can then add one Grunt to a friendly Faction small-based undead unit in this model’s control area. The Grunt must be placed in formation and within 3" of this model.</spell>
	<spell name="FIRE STEP" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="*" pow="13" up="NO" off="NO">Enemy models within 2" of this model suffer a POW 13 fire damage roll. After the damage is resolved, place this model completely within 3" of its current location. Fire Step can be cast only once per activation.</spell>
	<spell name="FLAGELLATION" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When making melee attacks, this model ignores both focus points overboosting the target’s Power Field and spell effects that add to its DEF or ARM. Models damaged by this model lose Tough and cannot be healed for one round.</spell>
	<spell name="GHOST WALK" cost="3" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains Ghostly for one turn. (When it advances, a model with Ghostly ignores movement penalties from terrain and obstacles and can advance through obstructions if it has enough movement to move completely past them. An affected model cannot be targeted by free strikes.)</spell>
	<spell name="HELLBOUND" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">This model cannot be targeted by charges. While within 5" of this model, enemy models treat open ground as rough terrain.</spell>
	<spell name="HELLFIRE" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="14" up="NO" off="YES">A model/ unit hit by Hellfire must pass a command check or flee.</spell>
	<spell name="HELLMOUTH" cost="4" rng="8" aoe="*" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">If this attack misses, nothing happens. If it hits, before making the damage roll, push models within 3" of the model hit 3" directly toward it in the order you choose. Then center a 3" AOE on the model hit. Models hit suffer a POW 12 damage roll. Models boxed by Hellmouth are removed from play.</spell>
	<spell name="HEX BLAST" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="3" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">Enemy upkeep spells and animi on the model/ unit directly hit by Hex Blast immediately expire.</spell>
	<spell name="HEX HAMMER" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When an enemy model casts a spell or uses an animus while in this model’s control area, after the spell or animus has been cast or used the enemy model suffers d3 damage points.</spell>
	<spell name="IGNITE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains +2 to melee attack damage rolls.  Affected models gain Critical Fire on their normal melee attacks.</spell>
	<spell name="IMMOLATION" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">Immolation causes fire damage. On a critical hit, the model hit suffer the Fire continuous effect</spell>
	<spell name="INFLUENCE" cost="1" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Take control of target enemy non—warcaster, non-warlock warrior model. The model immediately makes one normal melee attack, then Influence expires.</spell>
	<spell name="MAGE BLIGHT" cost="5" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model’s control area, living enemy models cannot cast spells or use feats. Mage Blight lasts for one round. </spell>
	<spell name="MAGE SIGHT" cost="2" rng="CTRL" aoe="5" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Place a 5'' AOE completely in this model's control area. While a model is within the AOE, models in this model's battlegroup ignore forests and cloud effects when drawing LOS to it and ignore Stealh when attacking it.</spell>
	<spell name="MARKED FOR DEATH" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">Target enemy model/ unit suffers -2 DEF and loses lncorporeal and Stealth and cannot gain those abilities while affected by Marked for Death. Friendly Faction models can target an affected model regardless of LOS.</spell>
	<spell name="MOBILITY" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Models in this model’s battlegroup currently in its control area gain +2 SPD and Pathfinder for one turn.</spell>
	<spell name="PARASITE" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">Target model/unit suffers -3 ARM and this model gains +1 ARM.</spell>
	<spell name="PURSUIT" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">If target enemy model/unit advances during its activation, immediately after ending this movement one model in this model’s battlegroup that is in its control area can make a full advance.</spell>
	<spell name="RIFT" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="4" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">The AOE is rough terrain and remains in play for one round.</spell>
	<spell name="SACRIFICIAL LAMB" cost="1" rng="CTRL" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Remove one friendly living Faction model in this model's control area from play to allocate l focus point to each warjack in this model's battlegroup that is currently in its control area. Sacrificial Lamb can be cast only once per turn.</spell>
	<spell name="SCOURGE" cost="4" rng="8" aoe="3" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">All models hit by Scourge are knocked down.</spell>
	<spell name="SCYTHING TOUCH" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains +2 to melee attack damage rolls. Affected models gain Critical Corrosion on their normal melee attacks.</spell>
	<spell name="SHADOWMANCER" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Models in this model’s battlegroup gain Dark Shroud and Stealth while in its control area. Shadowmancer lasts for one round. (While in the melee range of a model with Dark Shroud, enemy models suffer -2 ARM.) </spell>
	<spell name="SOUL GATE" cost="3" rng="CTRL" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Remove a friendly trooper model in this model’s control area from play and replace it with target warjack in this model’s battlegroup that is in its control area. LOS to that target is not required. The warjack cannot activate this turn after being placed by Soul Gate. </spell>
	<spell name="SUNDER SPIRIT" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES"> An enemy warbeast damaged by Sunder Spirit loses its animus for one round.</spell>
	<spell name="SYNERGY" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">While in its control area, models in this model’s battlegroup gain a +1 cumulative bonus on melee attack and melee damage rolls for each other model in the battlegroup that hit an enemy model with a melee attack this turn while in this model’s control area.</spell>
	<spell name="TELEPORT" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Place this model anywhere completely within 8" of its current location, then its activation ends.</spell>
	<spell name="TRANSFERENCE" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO"> While in this model's control area, friendly Faction non-warlock warrior models can spend 1 fury point on this model to boost a melee attack or melee damage roll during their activation.</spell>
	<spell name="TRUE PATH" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Friendly Faction warrior models/units beginning their activations in the model's control area gain +2” movement and Pathfinder during their activations. True Path lasts for one turn.</spell>
	<spell name="VENOM" cost="2" rng="SP8" aoe="-" pow="10" up="NO" off="YES">Venom causes corrosion damage. Models hit suffer the Corrosion continuous effect</spell>
	<spell name="VISION" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">The next time target friendly Faction model is directly hit by an attack, it suffers no damage roll from the attack, then Vision expires.</spell>
	<spell name="WALL OF FIRE" cost="2" rng="CTRL" aoe="WALL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Place the wall template anywhere completely within this model’s control area where it does not touch a model’s base, an obstruction, or an obstacle. When a model enters or ends its activation in the wall area, it suffers an unboostable POW l2 fire damage roll and the Fire continuous effect. Models within the wall template gain concealment.</spell>
	<!--  end of sorrted. -->
</spells>
