<spell name="ADMONITION" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When an enemy model advances and ends its movement within 6" of target model in this model’s battlegroup, the affected model can immediately advance up to 3", then Admonition expires. The affected model cannot be targeted by free strikes during this movement.</spell>
<spell name="AFFLICTION" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">When a damage roll resulting from a direct hit fails to exceed the ARM of the target enemy model/unit, the affected model hit suffers 1 damage point.</spell>
<spell name="ARCANTRIK BOLT" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">A warjack damaged by this attack becomes stationary for one round.</spell>
<spell name="BANISHING WARD" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Enemy upkeep spells on target friendly model/unit expire. Affected models cannot be targeted by enemy spells or animi.</spell>
<spell name="BATTEN DOWN THE HATCHES" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model's control area, models in its battlegroup cannot be knocked down and gain +3 ARM but suffer –2 DEF. Batten Down the Hatches lasts for one round.</spell>
<spell name="BLOW THE MAN DOWN" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="15" up="NO" off="YES">When a model is hit by Blow the Man Down, it is knocked down. On a critical hit, instead of suffering a normal damage roll, a non-incorporeal model is slammed d6" directly away from the spell's point of origin regardless of its base size. Collateral damage from this slam is POW 15.</spell>
<spell name="BLUR" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains +3 DEF against ranged and magic attack rolls.</spell>
<spell name="BREATH STEALER" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Target model/unit suffers –2 SPD and DEF for one round. Breath Stealer can be cast only once per turn.</spell>
<spell name="BROADSIDE" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Models in this model's battlegroup currently in its control area can immediately make one normal ranged attack. Attacks gained from Broadside do not count against a weapon's ROF. Broadside can be cast only once per turn.</spell>
<spell name="BULLET DODGER" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model gains +2 DEF against ranged attack rolls and Dodge, (A model with Dodge can advance up to 2" immediately after an enemy attack that missed it is resolved unless it was missed while advancing. It cannot be targeted by free strikes during this movement.)</spell>
<spell name="CALAMITY" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="YES">Friendly models gain +2 to attack and damage rolls against target enemy model/unit.</spell>
<spell name="CONVECTION" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">When Convection destroys a living enemy model, allocate 1 focus point to a warjack in this model's battlegroup that is in its control area.</spell>
<spell name="CONVECTION" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">When Convection destroys a living enemy model, allocate 1 focus point to a warjack in this model's battlegroup that is in its control area.</spell>
<spell name="COUNTERMEASURE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">While within 5" of target model/unit, enemy models cannot make ranged attacks.</spell>
<spell name="COUP DE MAIN" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Friendly models/units beginning a charge in this model's control area gain +2" movement. Affected models can charge without spending focus points or being forced. Coup de Main lasts for one round.</spell>
<spell name="CRUSADER'S CALL" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Friendly faction models beginning a charge while in this model's control area this turn gain +2" movement.</spell>
<spell name="DEADEYE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains an additional die on each model's first ranged attack roll this turn.</spell>
<spell name="DEADWEIGHT" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">When Deadweight destroys an enemy living or undead model, you can choose an enemy model within 2" of the destroyed model. The chosen model must forfeit either its movement or its action during its next activation, as its controller chooses.</spell>
<spell name="DEATH MARCH" cost="3" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly unit gains +2 MAT and Vengeance. (During your Maintenance Phase, if one or more models in a unit with Vengeance were destroyed or remove from play by enemy attacks during your opponent's last turn, each model in the unit can advance 3" and make one normal melee attack.)</spell>
<spell name="DECELERATION" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model’s control area, friendly models gain +2 DEF and ARM against ranged attacks. Deceleration lasts for one round.</spell>
<spell name="DISTRACTION" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Target enemy warrior model/unit cannot make ranged attacks and suffers –2 DEF and MAT for one round.</spell>
<spell name="EMPATHIC OVERLOAD" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="4" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">Models hit by Empathic Overload suffer a POW 12 damage roll. When Empathic Overload targets a friendly model, it automatically hits.</spell>
<spell name="ENERGIZER" cost="*" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model spends up to 3 focus points to cast Energizer. Models in its battlegroup that are currently in its control area can immediately advance up to 1" for each focus point spent. Energizer can be cast only once per turn.</spell>
<spell name="ERUPTION" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="3" pow="14" up="NO" off="YES">Models hit suffer a POW 14 fire damage roll. The AOE is a cloud effect that remains in play for one round. Models entering or ending their activation in the AOE suffer an unboostable POW 14 fire damage roll.</spell>
<spell name="EXPLOSIVO" cost="1" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">When target friendly model makes a normal attack with a non-spray ranged weapon, the weapon gains Magical Weapon. If the weapon was AOE - it becomes AOE 3. An affected model cannot participate in a combined ranged attack. Models in the AOE other than the model that was directly hit suffer blast damage rolls but do not suffer any other effects of the attack. Explosivo expires immediately after resolving target model's next ranged attack. Explosivo lasts for one turn.</spell>
<spell name="FAIL SAFE" cost="3" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly warjack gains +2 ARM and does not suffer the effects of crippled systems.</spell>
<spell name="FIRE FOR EFFECT" cost="3" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Boost the attack and damage rolls of target friendly Faction model's first ranged attack each activation.</spell>
<spell name="FIRE GROUP" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model's control area, the ranged weapons of models in its battlegroup gain +2 RNG. Fire Group lasts for one turn.</spell>
<spell name="FLASHING BLADE" cost="1" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">This model immediately makes one normal melee attack with one of its melee weapons against each enemy model in its LOS that is in the weapon's melee range. These attacks are simultaneous.</spell>
<spell name="FORTUNE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly Faction model/unit can reroll its missed attack rolls. Each attack roll can be rerolled only once as a result of Fortune.</spell>
<spell name="GALLOWS" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">When an enemy model is hit by this attack, it can be pushed d6" directly toward Gallow's point of origin.</spell>
<spell name="GALLOWS" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">When an enemy model is hit by this attack, it can be pushed d6" directly toward Gallows' point of origin.</spell>
<spell name="GROUND ZERO" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="5" pow="13" up="NO" off="NO">Center a 5" AOE on this model. Each other model in the AOE is hit and suffers a POW 13 damage roll. Each enemy model damaged by Ground Zero is pushed d6" directly away from this model in the order you choose.</spell>
<spell name="HAUNTING MELODY" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">While in this model's control area, living enemy models cannot give or receive orders and cannot make melee or ranged attacks targeting this model.</spell>
<spell name="HEX BLAST" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="3" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">Enemy upkeep spells and animi on the model/unit directly hit by Hex Blast immediately expire.</spell>
<spell name="HOT SHOT" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target model in this model's battlegroup gains boosted ranged attack damage rolls.</spell>
<spell name="INFLUENCE" cost="1" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Take control of target enemy non-warcaster, non-warlock warrior model. The model immediately makes one normal melee attack, then Influence expires.</spell>
<spell name="INHOSPITABLE GROUND" cost="3" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model's control area, enemy models treat open terrain as rough terrain. Inhospitable Ground lasts for one round.</spell>
<spell name="IRON AGGRESSION" cost="3" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly warjack can run, charge, or make slam or trample power attacks without spending focus and gains boosted melee attack rolls.</spell>
<spell name="JACKHAMMER" cost="1" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target model in this model's battlegroup immediately makes one normal melee attack.</spell>
<spell name="MISTWALKER" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Target model in this model's battlegroup gains Pathfinder and Prowl for one round. (Models with Prowl gain Stealth while within terrain that provides concealment, the AOE of a spell that provides concealment, or the AOE of a cloud effect.)</spell>
<spell name="MOBILITY" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Models in this model's battlegroup currently in its control area gain +2 SPD and Pathfinder for one turn.</spell>
<spell name="MOLTEN METAL" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Target warjack suffers 1 point of fire damage to each column on its damage grid.</spell>
<spell name="MOVING SHADOWS" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">While in this model's control area, models in its battlegroup gain Gun &amp; Run. (At the end of its activation, if it destroyed one or more enemy models with ranged attacks that activation, a model with Gun &amp; Run can make a full advance.)</spell>
<spell name="NONOKRION BRAND" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit ignores intervening models when making attacks. The weapons of affected models gain Magical Weapon.</spell>
<spell name="OBLITERATION" cost="4" rng="10" aoe="4" pow="15" up="NO" off="YES">The force of this attacks blasts apart the earth itself.</spell>
<spell name="ONSLAUGHT" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Friendly Faction models beginning a charge in this model's control area gain Pathfinder during the charge.</spell>
<spell name="PERSEVERANCE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly Faction model/unit gains +2 ARM, cannot be pushed and cannot be moved by a slam or throw.</spell>
<spell name="PHANTASM" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When target friendly model/unit is targeted by a ranged attack, the attack suffers –5 RNG.</spell>
<spell name="PIGPEN" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="*" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">While within 3" of this model, enemy models treat open terrain as rough terrain.</spell>
<spell name="POWDER KEG" cost="4" rng="10" aoe="5" pow="14" up="NO" off="YES">On a critical hit, models hit lose their initial attacks and cannot make special attacks for one round.</spell>
<spell name="PRIMED" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly warrior model/unit gains +2 to melee attack and melee damage rolls but suffers –2 ARM. If an affected model is disabled by an enemy attack, center a 3" AOE on it and remove that model from play. Models in the AOE are hit and suffer an unboostable POW 14 blast damage roll.</spell>
<spell name="PSYCHO SURGERY" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">Each model in this model's battlegroup currently in its control area immediately heals d3+1 damage points. The spell can only be cast once per turn.</spell>
<spell name="QUICKEN" cost="3" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model/unit gains +2 SPD and +2 DEF against ranged and magic attack rolls.</spell>
<spell name="RAMPAGER" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Take control of target enemy non-character warbeast. You can make one full advance with the warbeast and can then make one normal attack with it, then Rampager expires. While the warbeast is affected by Rampager, it cannot be forced and you cannot use its animus. Rampager can be cast only once per turn.</spell>
<spell name="REDLINE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target warjack in this model’s battlegroup gains +2 STR and SPD and can run, charge, or make power attack slams or tramples without spending focus. When it ends its activation, it suffers d3 damage points.</spell>
<spell name="RIFT" cost="3" rng="8" aoe="4" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">The AOE is rough terrain and remains in play for one round.</spell>
<spell name="ROCK WALL" cost="2" rng="CTRL" aoe="WALL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Place a wall template anywhere completely in this model's control area where it does not touch a model's base, an obstruction, or an obstacle. The wall is a linear obstacle that provides cover.</spell>
<spell name="ROTH'S MERCY" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When an enemy attack disables a friendly model in the target friendly unit, you can choose a non-disabled living model in the unit to be destroyed. If another model is destroyed as a result of Roth's Mercy, the originally disabled model heals 1 damage point.</spell>
<spell name="SNIPE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly model's/unit's ranged weapons gain +4 RNG.</spell>
<spell name="SOLID GROUND" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">While in this model's control area, friendly models cannot be knocked down and do not suffer blast damage.</spell>
<spell name="SOULFIRE" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="12" up="NO" off="YES">When a living non-soulless model is boxed by Soulfire, this model gains 1 focus point and the boxed model is removed from play.</spell>
<spell name="STONEHOLD" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Enemy models roll one less die on attack damage rolls against this model. This model and friendly models B2B with it cannot be knocked down.</spell>
<spell name="STORM RAGER" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly warrior model gains +2 STR, MAT, and ARM and cannot be targeted by combined ranged attacks or combined melee attacks.</spell>
<spell name="STRANGLEHOLD" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="-" pow="11" up="NO" off="YES">A model damaged by Stranglehold forfeits either its movement or its action during its next activation, as its controller chooses.</spell>
<spell name="STRENGTH OF GRANITE" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target model in this model's battlegroup gains +4 STR.</spell>
<spell name="SUNBURST" cost="3" rng="10" aoe="3" pow="13" up="NO" off="YES">Models boxed by Sunburst are removed from play. Blast damage affects only enemy models.</spell>
<spell name="SURE FOOT" cost="3" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly Faction model gains +2 DEF and cannot be knocked down. While within 3" of the affected model, friendly Faction models also gain +2 DEF and cannot be knocked down.</spell>
<spell name="TELEKINESIS" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="*">Place target model completely within 2" of its current location. When Telekinesis targets an enemy model, it is an offensive spell and requires a magic attack roll. A model can be affected by Telekinesis only once per turn.</spell>
<spell name="TELGESH MARK" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">This model can channel spells through targed friendly model as if it were a model in this model's battlegroup with Arc Node.</spell>
<spell name="TEMPER METAL" cost="2" rng="6" aoe="-" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Target friendly warjack gains +2 ARM and is immune to continuous effects.</spell>
<spell name="TRANSFERENCE" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">While in this model's control area, friendly Faction non-warcaster warrior models can spend 1 focus point on this model to boost a melee attack or a melee damage roll during their activations.</spell>
<spell name="TWISTER" cost="2" rng="10" aoe="3" pow="10" up="NO" off="YES">The AOE is a cloud effect that remains in play for one round.</spell>
<spell name="UNSTOPPABLE FORCE" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="NO" off="NO">While in this model's control area, models in its battlegroup gain Bulldoze. Unstoppable Force lasts for one turn. (When a model with Bulldoze advances into B2B contact with an enemy model during its activation, it can push that model up to 2" directly away from it. A model can be pushed by Bulldoze only once per activation. Bulldoze has no effect when a model makes a trample power attack.)</spell>
<spell name="VEIL OF MISTS" cost="3" rng="CTRL" aoe="4" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">Place a 4" AOE cloud effect anywhere completely in this model’s control area. This AOE does not block friendly Faction models' LOS. While in the AOE, friendly Faction models gain Pathfinder ICON and can move through obstructions and other models if they have enough movement to move completely past them.</spell>
<spell name="VOODOO DOLL" cost="2" rng="8" aoe="-" pow="-" up="NO" off="YES">Choose one of target enemy warbeast's aspects. That aspect suffers the effects of being lost for one round. A warbeast cannot be destroyed as a result of Voodoo Doll.</spell>
<spell name="WARPATH" cost="2" rng="SELF" aoe="CTRL" pow="-" up="YES" off="NO">When a friendly Faction model in this model's control area destroys one or more enemy models with a melee or ranged attack during its activation, immediately after the attack is resolved, one warjack in this model's battlegroup that is in its control area can advance up to 3". A warjack can advance only once per turn as a result of Warpath.</spell>
